Guide to the Victor S. Navasky Papers TAM.594
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: The Hollywood Blacklist and Naming Names, 1935-2013
  - Subseries IVA: Research and Related Materials
    - Motion Picture Association of American (MPAA) Files (notes), undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Motion Picture Industry Council (MPIC), 1951-1952, undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Murphy, George (Senator), 1979 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - "Myerson, HUAC" (includes "Committee on Internal Security Annual Report for the Year 1971"), 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Neier, Aryeh, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - New Leader: "No Compromise, Additional Thoughts on the Propriety of 'All My Sons' Here or Abroad", undated (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Newman, Edwin: Interview transcript - Elia Kazan on NBC "Speaking Freely", 1972 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Oates, Titus, undated (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - "The Odd Couple Revisited and Other Re-evaluations of American Communism and Anti-communism", 1978 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Odets, Clifford, 1975, undated (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Odlum, Floyd, 1947, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - O'Flaherty, Liam, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - O'Neil, James P., 1952 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Ophuls, Marcel, 1977, undated (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Orans, Alice: "In the Matter of Alice Orans, Brief of Alice Orans on Appeal", 1953 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Orans, Alice: Letters to Frank Donner and related notes (also includes several biographies of Sterling Hayden), 1940, 1950-1955 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Orans, Alice: Originals of Donner letters and related notes, 1953-1955 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Organization and Theme, undated (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Parks, Larry, 1951, 1975, undated (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Parks, Larry: FBI file, 1944-1960 (Box 26, Folder 42-43)
    - Parrish, Robert: Annotated pages from Growing Up in Hollywood, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Passports: News clippings re: Passport Study, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Peck, Sy, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Philbrick, Herbert A.: Notes on I Led Three Lives, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Pierre, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Pincus, Walter, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Poe, Elizabeth: "The Hollywood Story" and "A New Attack on an Old Evil", 1954, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Polan, Lou: Notes from 1955 testimony, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "Political Dictionaries: A Bibliographical Essay" by Clement E. Vose, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Popper, Martin, 1959, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Powell, Tristram, 1972-1976 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Pritt, Denis Nowell, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - "Private Ethics and Civic Virtue" by Lee C. McDonald, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Proctor, James, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Quackenbush, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Questions: Unanswered, 1976, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Quotations, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Radosh, Ron: Notes and articles (many from "Radosh Biblio"), 1950-1968 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Rapaport, Abraham: Notes on The Informer in Jewish Literature, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Rauh, Joseph L. Jr.: Includes articles on representation before congressional committees, 1959, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Raymond, James, undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Red Channels, 1978, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Redlich, Norman (re: Elizabeth Bentley), undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Reich, Walter M.D.: "Diagnosing Soviet Dissidents", 1978 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Reisman, David, undated (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Reitman, Alan: Notes from The Pulse of Freedom: American Liberties: 1920-1970s, undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Remington, William, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - "Report on Blacklisting" by John Cogley: Editorial comments, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Research: Various articles and notes, 1975-1976, undated (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Research and publication support: Address book (and various items that were folded between pages), 1975, undated (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Research and publication support: Calendar, annotated (daily reminder), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Research and publication support: Calendar pages, annotated, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Research and publication support: Calendar pages, annotated (full year), 1975 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Research and publication support: Calendar pages, annotated (full year), 1976 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Research and publication support: California trip, June 1976 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Research and publication support: Comments (from outside readers), 1978-1980, undated (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Research and publication support: Comments - Editorial (primarily involves editor Elisabeth Sifton and Research Assistant Karen Wilcox), 1979-1980, undated (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Research and publication support: Correspondence (legal issues), 1970-1980 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Research and publication support: Expense sheets, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Research and publication support: Naming Names syndication, undated (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Research and publication support: People to see, undated (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Research and publication support: Viking Press (Viking Penguin) - Includes initial agreement (Jan 26, 1972), 1972, 1980-1981, undated (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - "Research on the Informer and Collaborator for Victor Navasky's Book on the Sociology of the Informer..." by Marilyn Silverman, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Reuben, Bill, undated (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Rhodes, Silas H., 1976 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Ribuffo, Leo: "The Brown Scare: A 'Paranoid Style' in American Politics" and "Gerald L.K.Smith, American Liberals and Civil Liberties", 1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Richards, Sylvia, 1953, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Riefenstahl, Leni, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Rintels, Daniel, 1976, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Ritt, Martin and Walter Bernstein, 1979, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Rivkin, Allen, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Robards, Jason, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Robeson, Paul, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Robinson, Earl, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Robinson, Edward G., 1972 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Roche, John P., undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Rogge, O. John, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Role of the press, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Roos, Joseph, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Rosenberg children, 1973-1976 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1952-1953, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1952-1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Rosenman, Mervin, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Rossen, Robert, 1951. undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Rossen, Stephen: Notes and interview transcript concerning Robert Rossen, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Rossen, Susan, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Rosten, Norman, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Rosten, Leo C., 1947 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Rovere, Richard: Includes "The Kept Witnesses", 1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Russian Purge, The Theories: Photocopy of book chapter with Navasky annotations, undated (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Salem: Article "Satan in Salem", 1974 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Salt of the Earth (film), 1976, undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Salt, Waldo, undated (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Saltzman, Jack, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Sarbanes, Paul (articles cited by Paul Sarbanes in his Princeton senior thesis - "The Smith Act: A Denial of American Freedoms"), 1950s (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Sayre, Nora, undated (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Schary, Dore, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr. (includes photocopies of columns and articles 1947-1954), 1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr.: "The US Communist Party," LIFE, July 29, 1946 (also includes Navasky notes), undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Schulberg, Budd, undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Schulberg, Budd: Articles and news clippings, 1941, 1952, 1972-1975 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Schulberg, Budd: Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Schrecker, Ellen, undated (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Schreiber, Sidney, undated (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Scott, Joan, undated (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Scott, Robert Adrian, 1955, 1972, undated (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Shoenfeld, Bernard C., undated (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Sight and Sound: Volume 24 No. 3 and Volume 24 No. 4 (each contains an article re: On the Waterfront), 1955 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Sklar, George, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Skvorecky, Josef (two letters from Skvorecky to Navasky), 1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Smith Act, 1977, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Art, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Social Action Collection of the State Historical Society of Wisconsin: Inventory, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sorrell, Herbert: "You Don't Choose Your Friends: The Memoirs of Herbert Knott Sorrell", 1963 (Box 29, Folder 6-8)
    - Steinbeck, John: "The Trial of Arthur Miller", 1957 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Berkeley, Martin, Sep 19, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Blankfort, Michael, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Bromberg, J. Edward, Jun 20, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Dmytryk, Ed, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Gordon, Michael, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Huggins, Roy, Sep 30, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Kazan, Elia, Apr 10, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Lawrence, Marc, Apr 24, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Lennart, Isobel, undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Levy, Melvin, Jan 28, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Parks, Larry (also statements by Charlotte Adams, Roland Kibbee, Babbette Lang and Lee J. Cobb), Mar 21, 1951, Jun 2, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Raksin, David, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Richards, Sylvia, Mar 25, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Rossen, Robert, May 7, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Sabinson, Lee S., Zachary Schwartz, Robert Rossen, May 7, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Townsend, Leo, Sep 18, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Various, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Testimony (HUAC): Wilson, Elizabeth, Sep 20, 1951-Sep 21, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Testimony (unidentified), undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Testimony [Young, Nedrick, et al v. Motion Picture Association of America et al.], circa 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 29-30)
    - "To Name or Not to Name" (Navasky's New York Times Magazine article on Blacklisting): Correspondence and draft, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - "To Name or Not to Name": Research, notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Townsend, Leo, 1974, undated (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Trumbo, Dalton, 1973-1976, undated (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Trumbo, Dalton, 1976, undated (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Van Dyke, Willard, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - United States v. Huss: Transcript, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 37-39)
    - Vaughn, Robert, 1970, 1975, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Annenberg, Adelaide Klein, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Backus, Georgia, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Barzman, Ben, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Biberman, Herbert and Gale Sondergaard, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Buchman, Harold, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Cole, Lester, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Corey, Jeff, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Cunningham, Sarah (Mrs. John Randolph), 1970 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Dimsdale, Howard, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Farmer, Mary Virginia, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Geer, Will, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Gordon, Michael, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Hobart, Rose, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Houseman, John, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Jarrico, Paul, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Kazan, Elia, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Kilian, Victor, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Kraft, Hy, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Lang, David, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Lardner, Ring Jr., 1970 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Lawson, John Howard, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Lee, Madeline, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Lees, Robert, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Manson, Alan, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Ottenheimer, Albert M., 1970 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Polan, Lou, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Randolph, John, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Richards, Robert L., 1970 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Robison, David, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Sloane, Allan, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Tarloff, Frank, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Townsend, Pauline Swanson, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Traube, Sheppard, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Various, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Wanamaker, Sam, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Wexley, John, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Vaughn, Robert: Questionnaire responses - Wolfson, Martin, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Viva Zapata, 1951-1952, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Wechsler, James, 1976-1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Whitman, Alden, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Whitman, Alden (notes), undated (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - Wilson, Elizabeth, 1970, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Wilson, Michael and Rosanna Wilson, 1953, 1976, undated (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Willner, George, undated (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Witter, Charles (Office of Cornelius E. Gallagher, U.S. Congress, New Jersey): Letter concerning informer cases, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Young, Nedrick, et al. v. Motion Picture Association of America, Inc. et al, 1960, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Young, Nedrick, et al. v. Motion Picture Association of America, Inc. et al: Affadavits of Motion Picture Executives, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Young, Nedrick, et al. v. Motion Picture Association of America, Inc. et al: Exhibits, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - Rolodex, undated (Box 30)
    - Naming Names: Notes, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1997-2002 (Box 108)
  - Subseries IVB: The Writing Process
    - Notes: Chapter notes/notes on sources, undated (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes: Early outlines and preliminary notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
    - Notes: Section/Part 1, 1977, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Notes: Section/Part 1 and Section/Part 2 (mix), 1978, undated (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
    - Notes: Section/Part 2, undated (Box 31, Folder 8-10)
    - Notes: Section/Part 3, undated (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
    - Notes: Section/Part 4, undated (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
    - Notes: Section/Part 5, undated (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
    - Notes: Epilogue, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Notes: General, undated (Box 32, Folder 1-6, Box 31, Folder 18-19)
    - Drafted material with notes: Introduction, undated (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    - Drafted material with notes: Section/Part 1 and Section/Part 2, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Drafted material with notes: Section/Part 2, undated (Box 32, Folder 10-14)
    - Drafted material with notes: Section/Part 3, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Drafted material with notes: Section/Part 4, undated (Box 32, Folder 16-17)
    - Drafted material with notes: Epilogue, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Drafted material with notes: General, undated (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
    - Drafts: Foreword, undated (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
    - Drafts: Introduction, undated (Box 33, Folder 9-16)
    - Drafts: Section/Part 1, undated (Box 33, Folder 17-19, Box 34, Folder 1-5)
    - Drafts: Section/Part 2, undated (Box 34, Folder 6-11)
    - Drafts: Section/Part 3, undated (Box 34, Folder 12, Box 35, Folder 1-7)
    - Drafts: Section/Part 4, undated (Box 35, Folder 8-14)
    - Draft Fragments: [Section/Part 1], undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Draft Fragments with corrections: General, undated (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
    - Draft Fragments: General, undated (Box 35, Folder 18-20)
    - Typescript with corrections (heavily annotated), Jan 1980 (Box 36, Folder 1-4, Box 35, Folder 21-22)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 5-8)
    - Typescript with corrections (photocopy), undated (Box 36, Folder 9-13)
    - Typescript with minor corrections, undated (Box 36, Folder 14, Box 37, Folder 1-3)
    - Proofs: First proofs (researcher's copy), Feb 1980 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Proofs: Page proofs (author's set), undated (Box 37, Folder 5-7)
    - Proofs: Page proofs with corrections (general), undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Galley proof, Feb 1980 (Box 37, Folder 9-10)
  - Subseries IVC: Post Publication
    - Agreement: French translation, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Articles: Various, 1981-1990, 2003-2007 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Children of the Blacklist, 1989, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "The Cold War at Rutgers University: A Case Study of the Dismissals of Professors Heimlich, Finley, and Glasser" by Thomas F. Richards, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Corrections (correspondence pointing out errors), 1981, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1995, 2005-2013, undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - "George Sokolsky and the Anti-Communist Crusade" by Katrina van den Heuvel (seminar paper), 1980 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Holliday, Judy (material taken primarily from internet site- "The Judy Holliday Resource Center"), 2004 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - "Leaving the Party: the Politics of Sterling Hayden": Article in The New Criticism (Jan 1988), 1987, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Matusow, Harvey (Job): Update, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - McCarthy speech file, 1979-1981 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - McCarthy speech file: Can It Happen Again?, 1980, 1990, undated (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Navasky notes on memoirs by Budd Schulberg and Lester Cole, undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - New Edition (Naming Names revisited), 1994-2000, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Reviews (Naming Names), 1980-1982, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Robbins, Jerome, 1980-1999 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Security and Terrorism Subcommittee of the Senate Judiciary Committee (US repression), 1980-1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Tender Comrades (film project), undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "Value Judgments" Guest Lectures at Pratt (Navasky's lecture- "Individual Choices" includes transcript and photographs), Mar 23, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "The Value of Names: A Bill of Related Plays" by Jeffrey Sweet, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 7)
- Series V: Opinion Journalism and A Matter of Opinion, 1903-2008
  What was initially proposed as a long essay, a third person meditation on the role of opinion journalism, became, instead, a first person series of what Victor Navasky calls "misadventure stories." A Matter of Opinion is part history, part memoir, part organizational biography, and a paean to journals of opinion. Winner of the 2005 George Polk Book Award, Navasky describes the book's evolution in a 2004 speech (see Box 46, Folder 21).
  This series includes a significant amount of research material. Contained in two subseries, the research covers a wide variety of topics and individuals. There are also products of the writing process, such as drafted material and a typescript, as well as exchanges with various individuals who were editing and fact checking. Post publication and publicity materials are also included.
  - Subseries VA: Opinion Journalism File
    This subseries consists of a group of file folders (more than five linear feet), with original numbers and titles, containing material on the topic of opinion journalism, presumably research for A Matter of Opinion. There are folders for The Nation and for many other journals of opinion. In addition, the material covers such topics as objectivity, ideology, bias, censorship, ethics, and the publishing business in general. In the folders labeled "Individuals" may be found research on journalists, pundits, editors, publishers and writers of all kinds. There are a number of folders containing untitled notebooks.
    Not all of the sequential numbers appear in the list of folders (4,16,17,and 20 are skipped). It is possible that these had been removed or, perhaps, the material was re-labeled and used in some other context.
    - "1) General History and Intellectual Foundations", 1903-1948 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "1) General History and Intellectual Foundations", 1952-1989 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "1) General History and Intellectual Foundations", 1990-2001, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "2A) Nation History", 1904-1944 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - "2A) Nation History", 1951-1981 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "2A) Nation History", 1983-1997 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "2A) Nation History", undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - "2A) Nation: Articles About", 1976-2002, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - "2B) The New Republic", 1914, 1924, 1936, 1940, 1952-1989 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - "2B) The New Republic", 1991-2002 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - "2B) The New Republic", undated (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - "2C) The Weekly Standard", 1995-1996, undated (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - "2E) The Spectator", 1978-2001, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "2F) New Statesman", 1956-2002 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "2F) New Statesman", undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "2G) Partisan Review", 1934-2002, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "2H) All Others", 1963-1993, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "2H) All Others", 1983-2002, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "2I) New Leader", 1961-1997, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "2J) Mother Jones", 1977-2001 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "2J) The Commonweal", 1924-1964 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "2J) The Commonweal", 1974-2000 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "2K) The Christian Century", 1930-1994, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "3) Critical Journals: General", 1946-1993 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - "3) Critical Journals: General", 1995-2001, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - "3) Critical Journals: Prospect I; Anniversary Issues", 1917-1982, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - "3) Critical Journals: Prospect I; Anniversary Issues", 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - "3) Critical Journals: Prospect I; Anniversary Issues", 1986-1990 (Box 39, Folder 16)